monstersupplements.com 2019-04-14

# Privacy Policy | Monster Supplements

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

Our Privacy Policy was developed as an extension of our commitment to combine the highest-quality products and services with the highest level of integrity in dealing with our clients and partners. The Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site and our products and services. This statement will be continuously assessed against new technologies, business practices and our customers' needs.

**What Information Do We Collect?**

When you visit our Web site you may provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis and Web site use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our Web site.

**1\. Personal Information You Choose to Provide**

Personal Information

If you choose to request further information on our products or services from us or our partners, you may need to give personal information and authorization to obtain this information. For example, you may need to provide the following information:

Name   
Mailing address   
Email address   
Home and business phone number   
Other personal information (e.g. mother's maiden name)   
Email Information

In addition to providing the foregoing information to our partners, if you choose to correspond further with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received by mail and telephone.

**2\. Web Site Use Information**

Similar to commercial Web sites, our Web site utilizes a standard technology called "cookies" (see explanation below, What Are Cookies?) and Web server logs to collect information about how our Web site is used. Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Web site, and the Web sites visited just before and just after our Web site. This information is collected on an aggregate basis. None of this information is associated with you as an individual.

**How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?**

Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering our business activities, providing customer service and making available other products and services to our customers and prospective customers. Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Web site, new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. The lists used to send you product and service offers are developed and managed under our traditional corporate standards designed to safeguard the security and privacy of our customers' personal information. As a customer, you will be given the opportunity, at least once annually, to notify us of your desire not to receive these offers.

**What Are Cookies?**

Cookies are a feature of Web browser software that allows Web servers to recognize the computer used to access a Web site. Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a user's Web browser on the user's hard drive. Cookies can remember what information a user accesses on one Web page to simplify subsequent interactions with that Web site by the same user or to use the information to streamline the user's transactions on related Web pages. This makes it easier for a user to move from Web page to Web page and to complete commercial transactions over the Internet. Cookies should make your online experience easier and more personalized.

**How Do We Use Information We Collect from Cookies?**

We use Web site browser software tools such as cookies and Web server logs to gather information about our Web site users' browsing activities, in order to constantly improve our Web site and better serve our customers. This information assists us to design and arrange our Web pages in the most user-friendly manner and to continually improve our Web site to better meet the needs of our customers and prospective customers.

Cookies help us collect important business and technical statistics. The information in the cookies lets us trace the paths followed by users to our Web site as they move from one page to another. Web server logs allow us to count how many people visit our Web site and evaluate our Web site's visitor capacity. We do not use these technologies to capture your individual email address or any personally identifying information about you although they do permit us to send focused online banner advertisements or other such responses to you.

Monster Supplements use your personal data:

  * to provide goods and services to you;
  * to make a tailored website available to you;
  * to manage any registered account(s) that you hold with us;
  * to verify your identity;
  * for crime and fraud prevention, detection and related purposes;
  * to contact you electronically about promotional offers and products and services which we think may interest you;
  * to enable Monster Supplements to manage customer service interactions with you; and
  * where we have a legal right or duty to use or disclose your information (for example in relation to an investigation by a public authority or in a legal dispute).

**What Are Cookies?**

Cookies are a feature of browser software that allows web servers to recognise the computer used to access a website. Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a user's web browser. Cookies can remember what information a user accesses on one web page to simplify subsequent interactions with that website by the same user or to use the information to streamline the user's transactions on related web pages. This makes it easier for a user to move from page to page and to complete transactions over the internet. Cookies should make your online experience easier and more personalised. The table below explains the cookies we use and why.

**MonsterSupplements.com**

**Strictly Necessary**

**Cookie**

| 

**Description**  
  
---|---  
  
Frontend

| 

Magento - Sesssion ID on the server.  
  
persistent_shopping_cart

| 

Magento - link to information about the shopper's cart and viewing history.  
  
external_no_cache

| 

Magento - Indicates if caching is disabled or enabled.  
  
**MonsterSupplements.com**

**Performance Cookies**

**Cookie**

| 

**Description**  
  
---|---  
  
_ga

| 

Google Analytics 2 years Used to distinguish users.  
  
_gaos

| 

Google Analytics  
  
_gaost

| 

Google Analytics  
  
_gat

| 

Google Analytics 1 minute Used to throttle request rate.  
  
**MonsterSupplements.com**

**Functionality Cookies**

**Cookie**

| 

**Description**  
  
---|---  
  
_et_id.278d2765b651b1f2.undefined

| 

RECOMMENDTRACKER – <http://tracking.recommend.pro/>  
  
optimizelyBuckets

| 

Optimizely.com A/B Testing  
  
optimizelySegments

| 

Optimizely.com A/B Testing  
  
optimizelyEndUserId

| 

Optimizely.com A/B Testing  
  
_et_ses.278d2765b651b1f2.undefined

| 

RECOMMENDTRACKER – <http://tracking.recommend.pro/>  
  
RECOMMENDTRACKER

| 

RECOMMENDTRACKER – <http://tracking.recommend.pro/>  
  
**Google Analytics**

When someone visits monstersupplements.com we use a third party service called Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to report on things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make, and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. Data is recorded purely for reporting purposes and to ensure that visitors to our website are able to find the correct products and pages they are searching for.

As of the 25th May 2018, our Google Analytics suite will retain data for a period of 26 months.

The retention period applies to user-level and event-level data associated with cookies, user-identifiers (e.g., User-ID) and advertising identifiers (e.g., DoubleClick cookies, Android’s Advertising ID, Apple’s Identifier for Advertisers).

When data reaches the end of the retention period, it is deleted automatically on a monthly basis.

**Web Banner Advertising**

If you visit our websites, you may receive personalised banner advertisements whilst browsing other websites.  Any banner advertisements you see will relate to products you have viewed whilst browsing our websites on your computer or other devices.

These advertisements are provided by Monster Supplements via market leading specialist providers using ‘cookies’ placed on your computer or other devices (see further information on the use of cookies in our Cookie Policy).  You can remove or disable cookies at any time - see below for further information.

**How to opt-out of Cookies**

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

**Notice of New Services and Changes**

Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Web site, new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. As our client, you will be given the opportunity to notify us of your desire not to receive these offers by clicking on a response box when you receive such an offer or by sending us an email request at info@monstersupplements.com.

**Evaluation of Information Protection Practices**

Periodically, our operations and business practices are reviewed for compliance with corporate policies and procedures governing the security, confidentiality and quality of our information.

**Employee Access, Training and Expectations**

Our corporate values, ethical standards, policies and practices are committed to the protection of customer information. In general, our business practices limit employee access to confidential information, and limit the use and disclosure of such information to authorized persons, processes and transactions.

**Do We Disclose Information to Outside Parties?**

We may provide aggregate information about our customers, sales, Web site traffic patterns and related Web site information to our affiliates or reputable third parties, but this information will not include personally identifying data, except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy.

**What About Legally Compelled Disclosure of Information?**

We may disclose information when legally compelled to do so, in other words, when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights.

**What About Other Web Sites Linked to Our Web Site?**

We are not responsible for the practices employed by Web sites linked to or from our Web site nor the information or content contained therein. Often links to other Web sites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our Web site.

Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Web site to another Web site, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other Web site, including Web sites which have a link on our Web site, is subject to that Web site's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

**  
Mailing Lists**

As part of the registration process for our e-newsletter, we may collect personal information. We use this information for a couple of reasons: to tell you about things you’ve asked us to tell you about; to contact you if we need to obtain or provide additional information; to check our records are right and to check every now and then that you’re happy and satisfied. We don't rent or trade email lists with other organisations and businesses.

We use a third-party provider called MailChimp, to deliver our newsletter. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletter. For more information, please see MailChimp’s privacy notice by Clicking Here.

You can unsubscribe from our promotional emails at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of our emails or by emailing our Customer Services team at support@monstersupplements.com

**  
Your Consent**

By using our Web site you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our Web site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

**Access to your personal information**

As part of our commitment to keeping your data private, you are fully entitled to view, amend or delete personal information that we hold.

To request information on your personal data or ask for us to delete any details we store, please email [support@monstersupplements.com](mailto:support@monstersupplements.com) or call 01482 60 60 22.

You can also write to us at:

Monster Supplements

Clay Street

Kingston upon Hull

East Yorkshire

HU8 8HA

Note: We may be required to continue storing certain personal data for legal reason e.g. tax purposes or proof of sales.

**How long do we keep your data?**

We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy. Different retention periods apply for different types of data, however the longest we will normally hold any personal data is 6 years.

**Changes to this Privacy Notice**

This Privacy Policy is reviewed regularly and is subject to amendment, without prior notification.

**Visitors to our website**

When someone visits [www.monstersupplements.com](https://monstersupplements.com/) we collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. We collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be up front about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it.

**Use of cookies by Monster Supplements**

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**YouTube cookies**

We embed videos from our official YouTube channel using YouTube's privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. To find out more please visit [YouTube's embedding videos information page](https://www.google.com/support/youtube/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=171780 "External link").
